Guide to the Charles L. Adams Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles L. Adams papers
1946-2002
WA MSS S-2615
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
31
(36 boxes)
The collection consists of material created and collected by Charles Adams in the course of his research and teaching activities as a scholar of Frank Waters and a professor of English at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas. Material includes correspondence; transcripts and sound recordings of interviews with Waters; sound recordings of various seminars, lectures, and talks about Waters; typescripts of writings by and about Waters; photocopies, reprints, and excerpts of published works by Waters; clippings and other printed material; teaching files; files relating to the Frank Waters Society; and other material. The collection documents Adams's academic career, which focused largely on Waters, and his role as a leading organizer of the scholarly and popular communities interested in Waters, particularly as founder of the Frank Waters Society and editor of Studies in Frank Waters. The collection also sheds light on the nature and organization of the community of interest that sprang up around Waters's work, and provides a great deal of information about Waters in the taped and transcribed interviews conducted by Adams and others.
Adams, Charles L.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joan and Rebecca Adams, 2008.
Custodial History
The collection was packed and shipped from Charles L. Adams's office at University of Nevada, Las Vegas by his daughter, Rebecca Adams.
Conditions Governing Access
Boxes 30-33 (Series VI. Audiovisual Material): Restricted pending digital reformatting. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 35 (electonic documents): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies available. Consult Access Services for further information.
Separated Materials
Certain books and publications from the Charles L. Adams Papers have been accessioned and cataloged separately, with their provenance traced. These items can be found by searching the Uncataloged Acquisitions Database and Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
Charles L. Adams (1929-2008)
Charles L. Adams was born in Joliet, Illinois, May 11, 1929. He earned his B.A. from Michigan State, his M.A. from the University of Illinois, and his Ph.D. from the University of Oregon. He was a professor of English at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas from 1960 to 1999.
Adams's specialty was modern literature, but he was particularly interested in the writings of Frank Waters, the southwestern novelist, essayist, biographer and non-fiction writer. Adams taught a two-semester series of courses on Waters and was a founder of the Frank Waters Society and editor of its annual journal. He edited Frank Waters: A Retrospective Anthology (Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1985) and, with Waters, co-edited W.Y. Evans-Wentz's Cuchama and Sacred Mountains (Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1981). He also published numerous articles on Waters and other literary topics in an assortment of journals. Adams was quoted as saying: "I find it very exciting to be able to work with a living author." Waters spoke in his classes and at UNLV's commencement, and Adams participated in numerous conferences and panels on, about, and with Waters.
This biographical note was excerpted from Adams's obituary posted on the Frank Waters Foundation website.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and collected by Charles Adams in the course of his research and teaching activities as a scholar of Frank Waters and a professor of English at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas. Material includes correspondence; transcripts and sound recordings of interviews with Waters; sound recordings of various seminars, lectures, and talks about Waters; typescripts of writings by and about Waters; photocopies, reprints, and excerpts of published works by Waters; clippings and other printed material; teaching files; files relating to the Frank Waters Society; and other material. The collection documents Adams's academic career, which focused largely on Waters, and his role as a leading organizer of the scholarly and popular communities interested in Waters, particularly as founder of the Frank Waters Society and editor of Studies in Frank Waters. The collection also sheds light on the nature and organization of the community of interest that sprang up around Waters's work, and provides a great deal of information about Waters in the taped and transcribed interviews conducted by Adams and others.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1970-2000. II. Transcripts of Interviews with Frank Waters, 1970-1990. III. Writings, Research, and Other Material, 1946-2002. IV. Frank Waters Society, 1975-2002. V. General and Teaching Files, 1960-2000. VI. Audiovisual Material, circa 1970-2000.
American literature -- Southwest, New -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Indians in literature; Western stories; Southwest, New -- In literature; West (U.S.) -- In literature; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Videocassettes; Adams, Charles L.; Waters, Frank, 1902-1995; Frank Waters Society; University of Nevada, Las Vegas
- Correspondence, 1970-2000; Series I; 3.42 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes photocopies of correspondence between Adams and Frank Waters. It is unknown where the originals are. Also included is Adams's correspondence with scholars, students, and colleagues.
  Arrangement
  Arranged into two subseries: Correspondence between Charles Adams and Frank Waters, and General Correspondence.
  - Correspondence between Charles Adams and Frank Waters
    All post-1995 correspondence is between Adams and Frank Waters's wife, Barbara. Some correspondence with Barbara Waters can also be found in the earlier files.
    Arranged chronologically by year.
    - 1971-1990 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1-20)
    - 1991-2000s 1991-2000s (Box 2, Folder 21-28)
  - General Correspondence
    Some correspondence with Frank Waters can be found in the general files, as well as some writings, research, and teaching material.
    Arranged alphabetically by surname of individual or by original folder headings.
    - "Academic correspondence", 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Adams, Rebecca, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Adams, Stephen Thomas, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Barnes, H. Lee, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bedard, Brian, 1974-1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Blackburn, Alex, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
    - Blevins, Louis, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Includes a pocket watch.
    - Bona, Albert, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
    - Carlson, Ingeborg, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Casagrande, Alan, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Dominguez, Marty, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Dutton, Dennis H., 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
    - Fagg, Wayne, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Farr, Don, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Frank Waters Society", 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
    - "Frank Waters Society", 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Gaiter, Marcia, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - German Contract, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Goode, Stephen, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Green, Larry, 1976-1980s (Box 3, Folder 53-56)
    - Grider, Daryl, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Gunter / Walker, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Haggerty, Pat, 1978-1980s (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Harrison, Dick, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Hastings, Arthur, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Huntress, Diana, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Ippolito, Donna, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Jenkins, Robin, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Keegan, Marcia, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Kostka, Bob, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Kretschmer, Eugene, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Lloyd, Susan, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Lopez, Ruth, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Lord, Paul, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Loudon, Michael, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Luciano, Angel, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Luther, Tal, 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
    - Lyon, Tom, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - McBride, Mary, 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence Re: Waters, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Nagel, Anna, 1970s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - FW - Nevada Press, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Panich, Holly, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Peters, Paul, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Pilkington, William, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Riese, John Gilch, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Schaefer, John, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - SOR issue, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Speaking of Frank Waters, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Tanner, Terrence, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 87-89)
    - Thorne, Joan Vail, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Todd. Edgeley, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 91)
- Transcripts of Interviews with Frank Waters, 1970-1990; Series II; 1; (1 box)
  This series consists transcripts of interviews with Frank Waters, the majority of which were conducted by Adams.
  Related Archival Materials note
  For sound recordings of interviews with Waters, see Audiovisual Material.
  - Adams Interview, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Notes of Frank Waters, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Sedona, January 1975 (Box 5, Folder 94-98)
  - Taos, July 1975 (Box 5, Folder 99-103)
  - Final Additions and Corrections for Taos 1975, Sedona 1975 and Sedona 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Sedona, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 105-110)
  - Adams at Stanford, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 111-112)
  - Tucson, January 1977 and Taos, August 1977 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Tucson, March 1982 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Talks With Frank Waters, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Tucson, April 1988 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - New America Project - Univerisity of New Mexico, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Interviews with Frank Waters, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 118)
- Writings, Research and Other Material, 1946-2002; Series III; 8.0 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Arranged into five subseries: Writings by Charles L. Adams, Writings by Others, Writings by Frank Waters, Other Research Material, and Printed Materials. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by supplied or original folder headings.
  This series consists of material relating to Adams's various research and writing efforts as a Frank Waters scholar. Material includes typescripts and copies of articles, essays, dissertations and other works about Waters, composed by Adams and other writers; photocopies and published copies of books by Waters that have been flagged and annotated by Adams; typescript copies of other writings by Waters. Also included are excerpts, reprints, and clippings of various articles and other printed material about Waters and related topics.
  - Writings by Charles L. Adams
    - "An Additional Function of Native American Literature", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Cuchama, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 120-127)
    - For Dr. Adam's Signature: Deer Article" (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Foreward to Blackburn Book, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - "Frank Waters", 1981 (Box 6, Folder 130)
      Includes a chapter from The Literary History of the American West.
    - Frank Waters File: Dutch, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Frank Waters: Introduction (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Frank Waters: Popular Unknown Author, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Frank Waters: A Retrospective Anthology, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 134-141)
    - Frank Waters: A Retrospective Anthology, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 142-143)
    - Frank Waters's 'Women' - HaveURead, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Intro to 'The Delta' (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - "The Literary History Of The American West", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Manby Review (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Misc. Ideas and Notes (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - "A Mountain In Your Front Yard", 1989 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - New Mexico 'Locus Amoenus', 1984-1990 (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - "Of Time & Change", 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Other Mountains Throughout the World, Part II (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Pop. Culture, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Reflections, Part IV (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - "The Return of Frank Waters", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Review Of 'Writing To Survive', 1989 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - River Trip, review, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Teaching Yogi in Las Vegas, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 158-160)
      Includes a copy of a 1991 letter from Waters to Adams, as well as an essay entitled "Las Vegas As Border Town".
    - "The Woman At Otowi Crossing", 1980s (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Writings by Others
    - "A Bibliography of Frank Waters, 1916-1981", by Terrance Tanner, manuscript (Box 7, Folder 162-165)
    - Campbell, Felicia, manuscript, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - "Father Sun, Mother Earth", 1976 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - "Following Martiniano's Footsteps: Finding The Center", by Robert A. Anderson, print out, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - "Frank Waters: An Appreciation", by Robert W. Smith, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - "Frank Waters and the Geopoetics of Mountain Worship". by Dennis H. Dutton, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - "Frank Waters and the Wild West", by Quay Grieg, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 171)
      See Also: Series VIII, Restricted Fragile, Computer Disks, Box 35.
    - "A House Without God", by H. Lee Barnes, print out, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - "Miles After Miles", 1980s (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - "The Mind Is Its Own Place, A Novella", by H. Lee Barnes, typescript" (Box 8, Folder 174-175)
    - "The Mora Valley", by Gary W. Rodgers, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 176-177)
    - "On Reading Frank Waters", by Alexander Blackburn, typescript, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Panelist writing, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - "Rightness With The Land: Spirit Of Place In The Novels Of Frank Waters", by David Aleck Grider, typescript, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Scholarly Papers, 1990s-2000s (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - "A Study of The Man Who Killed The Deer", by Christopher Earl Hoy, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - "A Sunrise Brighter Still", by Alexander Blackburn, typescript, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 183-186)
    - A Sunrise Brighter Still, by Alexander Blackburn, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - "The Woman At Otowi Crossing", reaction and screenplay, 1989-2002 (Box 8, Folder 188-189)
  - Writings by Frank Waters
    - Below Grass Roots, photocopy (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Book Of The Hopi, published copy annotated by Adams, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - "By Waters", 1970s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 192)
      Includes photocopies of various writings by Waters.
    - "By Waters", 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 193-194)
    - "The Changing and Unchangeable West", photocopy (Box 9, Folder 195)
    - The Colorado, published copy annotated by Adams, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - The Colorado, published copy annotated by Adams, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Current Literary Views, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Diamond Head, photocopies (Box 9, Folder 199-201)
    - The Dust Within The Rock, photocopies (Box 9, Folder 202-205)
    - Fever Pitch, photocopies (Box 9, Folder 206-207)
    - Flight From Fiesta, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 208-209)
    - "The Long Way Home", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - "The Long Way Home", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 211)
    - Masked Gods, 1950, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 212-213)
    - Mountain Dialogues, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 214)
    - Of Time & Change, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 215)
    - "The One Great Book of Life", 1985 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - Pike's Peak, published copy annotated by Adams, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - To Possess The Land, published copy annotated by Adams, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - River Lady (Box 10, Folder 219-222)
    - Robert Gilruth, photocopy (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - "The Spot", 1988 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - "Stories From Frank Waters" (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - The Wild Earth's Nobility (Box 11, Folder 226-227)
    - The Woman At Otowi Crossing, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 228-230)
  - Other Research Material
    - "30 Years Later - The Man Who Killed the Deer", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 231-233)
    - Annual Writer In Residence Lecture, Colorado State University, mimeograph, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - Chronology, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - Commencement Address, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - "Death and Redemption", 1970s (Box 11, Folder 237)
    - "It Might Just As Well Be Called Deer", 1988 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - "Las Vegas As Border Town" (Box 11, Folder 239)
      Includes "Frank Waters And The Concept of 'Nothing Special'".
    - Luther, T.N., 1989 (Box 11, Folder 240)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - Manuscript material removed from books, 1980s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 242)
    - Melvyl Online catalog, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 243)
    - Memories, Dreams, Reflections - Travels (Box 11, Folder 244)
    - Penwell, Clifford, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 245)
    - "Quetzalcoatl Versus D.H. Lawrence's Plumed Serpent", photocopy (Box 11, Folder 246-248)
      Includes photocopies of "The Fifth World - The Ninth Planet".
    - The Scarab Papers, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Small, Karen, photograph, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - "Trip Poem", by Victoria McCabe, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 251)
      Also includes "Southwest Heritage", by Mabel Major and T.M. Pearce and "Female Protagonist", by Frances Malpezzi.
    - Visual Material, including photographic slides and negatives, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 252)
    - Words, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 253-254)
      Also includes a photocopy of Frank Water's "The Fifth World - The Ninth Planet".
    - Writers' Forum, volume 15, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 255)
    - Writers' Forum, volume 11, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Printed Materials
    - AB: Bookman's Weekly, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 257-258)
    - The Adobe Press, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 259)
    - American Way, magazine, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 260)
    - The Atlantic, magazine and clippings, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 261)
    - The Bear, photocopy (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - Clippings, 1970s-1990s (Box 12, Folder 263-273)
      Includes newspaper clippings, some reviews of published material, photocopies and copies of various magazines.
    - Clippings, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 274-284)
    - Free Las Vegas Weekly, newspaper, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 285-286)
    - Fry Breads, Feast Days and Sheeps, by Kris Hotvedt, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 287)
    - Have You Read?, booklet and handout, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - Hawaii's Poisonous Plants, by Roger E. Baldwin Ph.D., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 289)
    - Magazines and clippings, 1976-1991 (Box 13, Folder 290-292)
    - Memorial / Obituary clippings - Frank Waters, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 293)
    - National Forum, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 294)
    - Nevada Southern University, catalog, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 295)
    - Opera Theater Of Saint Louis and The Woman at Otowi Crossing, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - Sundays in Tutt Library with Frank Waters, edited by Katherine Scott Sturdevant, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 297)
      Includes two copies of Sundays in Tutt Library with Frank Waters, both signed by Frank Waters.
- Frank Waters Society, 1975-2002; Series IV; 4.42 linear feet (6 boxes)
  This series includes material specifically related to the publication of the newsletters and the journal "Studies in Frank Waters", as well as to the Frank Waters Society itself.
  - Frank Waters Seminar, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 298)
  - Stanford Library - Cuchama Original, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 299)
  - Vault - Frank Waters, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Contribution Forum, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 301)
  - Studies In Frank Waters V - Frank Waters: Western Mystic, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 302-303)
  - Frank Waters Society Newsletter, 1983-1985 (Box 14, Folder 304)
  - Studies in Frank Waters V, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 305)
  - Studies in Frank Waters VI, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 306-309)
  - Studies in Frank Waters, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Studies - photocopy, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Frank Waters Seminar, pamphlet, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 312-314)
  - Henderson Programs, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Henderson, NV, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - Newsletter, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 317-319)
  - Studies in Frank Waters VII - An Appreciation, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 320-321)
  - Studies in Frank Waters VIII - Emergences, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Newsletter, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 323)
  - Newsletter, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 324)
  - Studies in Frank Waters VIII - Emergences, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 325-328)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XI - Time, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Frank Waters - Las Vegas, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 330)
  - Newsletter, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 331-332)
  - Studies in Frank Waters IX - Flight From Fiesta, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 333-335)
  - Call For Papers, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - Newsletter, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 337-338)
  - Studies in Frank Waters X - Connections, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 339-343)
  - Studies in Frank Waters Index, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 344)
  - Studies in Frank Waters X - Connections, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 345-346)
  - Membership, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 347)
  - Newsletter, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 348-350)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XI - Time, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 351)
  - Studies in Frank Waters IX - Flight From Fiesta, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - RE: Standing Orders, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 353)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVIII - Afterwards, 1989-1996 (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Newsletter, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 355-356)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XI - Time, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 357)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XII - The Novel, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 358-363)
  - Frank Waters Foundation, pamphlet, 1990s-2000s (Box 16, Folder 364)
  - Newsletter, 1990s-2000s (Box 16, Folder 365)
    Includes a notice regarding Frank Waters death, 1995.
  - FW PCA - 'Invitation To The Dance', 1991 (Box 16, Folder 366)
  - FWS (From 1991), 1990s-2000s (Box 16, Folder 367)
  - Newsletter, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 368-369)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XIII - The Land, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 370-373)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XIV - The People, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 374)
  - Call For Papers, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 375)
  - Frank Waters Chronology, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 376)
  - The Man Who Killed Deer, loose papers, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 377)
  - Newsletter, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 378-379)
  - Panel Discussion, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 380-381)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XIV - The People, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Newsletter, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XV - Readers, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 384-386)
  - Frank Waters Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 387)
  - Newsletter, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 388)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVI - Environmental Concerns, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 389-394)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XV - Readers, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 395)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVI - Environmental Concerns, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 396)
  - Brochures, 1995- (Box 17, Folder 397)
  - Frank Waters Chronology, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 398)
  - In Memorium, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 399-401)
  - ST-18, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 402)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVII - Vision, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 403)
  - Viewpoints and Vision, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 404)
  - Current Newsletter, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 405)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVII - Vision, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 406)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XVIII - Afterwards, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 407)
  - Radio, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 408)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XIX - Insights, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 409-410)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XIX - Insights, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 411)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XX - Explication, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 412)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XXI - Contributions, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 413-415)
  - Studies in Frank Waters XXII - Archive I, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 416-419)